Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and today we're going on a little driving lesson.
我是Catherine，今天我们要上一堂小小的驾驶课。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to learn how to drive, but not only how to drive, but all the vocabulary
我们要学习如何开车，但不仅仅是开车，还有所有与这项活动相关的词汇
and words associated to this activity.
和词语。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue for the first time and we'll be back to explain
所以我们先听一遍这段对话，然后回来解释
it.
它。
Okay, I'm ready for my driving lesson.
好的，我准备好上驾驶课了。
Should I start the car?
我可以发动车了吗？
Hold on there, Fittipaldi.
等等，Fittipaldi。
First let's go over things one more time.
首先，我们再过一遍内容。
Now before you even think of starting the car, make sure your seat is at a comfortable
在你甚至想发动车之前，确保你的座椅处于舒适
position and you can grip the steering wheel firmly.
的位置，并且你能牢牢握住方向盘。
Next, check your rearview mirrors to make sure you can see properly.
接下来，检查你的后视镜，确保你能看清楚。
We've been through this a million times.
这些我们已经讲过无数次了。
Let's get going already.
我们赶紧开始吧。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Fine.
好吧。
Start the car.
发动车。
Okay, now gently step on the clutch and shift to first gear.
好的，现在轻轻踩下离合器，换到一档。
Good.
很好。
Now, accelerate gently and let go of the clutch as you do it.
现在，轻轻加速，同时松开离合器。
There we go.
这就对了。
Good.
很好。
I'm doing it.
我正在做。
I'm driving.
我在开车。
This is awesome.
太棒了。
Let's turn some music on.
我们放点音乐吧。
Keep your eyes on the road.
眼睛看着路。
No music.
不许放音乐。
We are coming up to a red light.
我们快到红灯了。
Step on the brakes.
踩刹车。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I said the brakes.
我说踩刹车。
Look out for those people.
小心那些人。
Get off the sidewalk.
离开人行道。
Get out of my way.
别挡我的路。
This is just like playing video games.
这就像玩电子游戏一样。
It's the police.
是警察。
Pull over.
靠边停车。
They'll never take me alive.
他们休想活捉我。
All right.
好吧。
Great.
太好了。
So, it's a great driving lesson just like the video games.
所以，这堂驾驶课很棒，就像电子游戏一样。
Well, hopefully not like video games.
嗯，希望别像电子游戏那样。
We don't want to hurt anyone.
我们不想伤害任何人。
But that comes a little bit later.
但那稍后再说。
First, let's check out some of these very important phrases in today's Language Takeaway.
首先，让我们看看今天“语言要点”中的一些非常重要的短语。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
So, on Language Takeaway, we have five words for you today.
那么，在“语言要点”中，我们今天有五个词要介绍。
Starting with the first one, the steering wheel.
从第一个开始，方向盘。
Okay, steering wheel.
好的，方向盘。
So, this comes from the fact that we have a wheel that we use to turn the car left and
所以，这来源于我们有一个轮子，用来让车向左和
right.
向右转。
And so, that's called to steer, to change the direction of something.
这叫做“转向”，即改变某物的方向。
So, the verb to steer is to take it left or right.
所以，动词“转向”就是让它向左或向右。
Exactly.
没错。
So, steering wheel is the instrument that we use to change the car's direction.
所以，方向盘是我们用来改变汽车方向的工具。
Very good.
非常好。
And, well, apart from this instrument, also in order to look to other cars that are behind
而且，除了这个工具，为了观察你后面的其他车辆，
you, you would look at your rear view mirror.
你会看你的后视镜。
Great.
很好。
So, rear view mirror.
所以，后视镜。
This is a mirror that you have in front of you in the middle of the car.
这是你面前车中间的一个镜子。
And you look at this mirror to find out if there are cars behind you.
你看这个镜子是为了知道后面有没有车。
So, it's a rear view.
所以，它是“后方视野”。
That means you're looking at the back.
意思是你在看后面。
Rear means back or behind.
“Rear”意思是后面或背后。
What about the mirrors that are on the side of the car, on the doors?
那车侧面、车门上的镜子呢？
Those are called side view mirrors.
那些叫做侧视镜。
Side view mirrors.
侧视镜。
Very literal.
非常直白。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And, well, moving on, he was instructing her on how to drive and he said, step on the clutch.
而且，继续往下，他在指导她如何开车，他说“踩离合器”。
Well, this is an important word for those of you who are driving manual cars.
嗯，对于开手动挡车的人来说，这是一个重要的词。
It means that you have to control the way that the gas goes into the engine by yourself.
意思是你要自己控制汽油进入发动机的方式。
And so, a clutch is a pedal.
所以，离合器是一个踏板。
It's the third pedal on the left and you push this pedal to change gears.
它是左边第三个踏板，你踩这个踏板来换挡。
So, some cars, they don't have this.
所以，有些车没有这个。
For those of you who don't, don't worry about it.
对于那些没有的人，不用担心。
But if you do, a clutch is on the far left.
但如果你有，离合器在最左边。
It's the third pedal.
它是第三个踏板。
Okay, so this is for a manual car, manual transmission car because many people have
好的，所以这是针对手动挡车，手动变速箱车，因为很多人开
automatics where you just accelerate and the car automatically changes gears.
自动挡车，你只需加速，车就会自动换挡。
Exactly.
没错。
And so, a lot of Europeans drive manual cars and have this clutch.
而且，很多欧洲人开手动挡车，有这种离合器。
Okay, so you step on the clutch and in order to change gear, you say to shift into first gear.
好的，所以你踩下离合器，为了换挡，你说“换到一档”。
That's right because if you're driving, you know that you can't go from first to fifth gear, right?
没错，因为如果你开车，你知道你不能从一档直接换到五档，对吧？
There's four or five gears and so you have to go one, two, three, four, five.
有四或五个档位，所以你必须一、二、三、四、五。
You have to go in order.
你必须按顺序来。
So, we're shifting.
所以，我们在换挡。
We're moving up or we're moving down.
我们在升档或降档。
So, that's called to shift.
所以，这叫做“换挡”。
All right, to shift.
好的，换挡。
And now, in the dialogue, we heard to shift into first gear.
现在，在对话中，我们听到“换到一档”。
So, that's what it's called.
所以，这就是它的叫法。
Exactly.
没错。
And so, normally, the car starts in N, neutral.
而且，通常，车从N档，空档开始。
That was when you're at a break, you're at a stop.
那是当你停车或停下的时候。
And if you want to start the car, you have to shift to first gear and that's the lowest.
如果你想发动车，你必须换到一档，这是最低的。
That's going to help the car go.
这会让车动起来。
Okay, so to shift into first gear.
好的，所以“换到一档”。
Awesome vocabulary.
很棒的词汇。
I think this is really useful especially because it's very specific so you don't really see it very often in anywhere.
我觉得这非常有用，尤其是因为它很具体，所以你在别处不常看到。
But sometimes, you need to use it.
但有时，你需要用到它。
That's right and it's especially useful if you're trying to teach someone.
没错，而且如果你想教别人，这特别有用。
How to drive.
如何开车。
Yeah, because not everyone knows how to drive manual.
是啊，因为不是每个人都知道怎么开手动挡。
Exactly.
没错。
So, why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to explain Fluency Builder.
那么，我们再来听一遍对话，然后回来解释“流利度构建”。
Fluency Builder
流利度构建
Okay, I'm ready for my driving lesson.
好的，我准备好上驾驶课了。
Should I start the car?
我可以发动车了吗？
Hold on there, Fittipaldi.
等等，Fittipaldi。
First, let's go over things one more time.
首先，我们再过一遍内容。
Now, before you even think of starting the car, make sure your seat is at a comfortable position and you can grip the steering wheel firmly.
现在，在你甚至想发动车之前，确保你的座椅处于舒适的位置，并且你能牢牢握住方向盘。
Next, check your rear view mirrors to make sure you can see properly.
接下来，检查你的后视镜，确保你能看清楚。
We've been through this a million times.
这些我们已经讲过无数次了。
Let's get going already.
我们赶紧出发吧。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Fine, start the car.
好吧，发动车子。
Okay, now gently step on the clutch and shift to first gear.
好的，现在轻轻踩下离合器，挂到一档。
Good.
不错。
Now, accelerate gently and let go of the clutch as you do it.
现在，轻轻加速，同时松开离合器。
There we go.
这就对了。
Good.
不错。
I'm doing it.
我正在做呢。
I'm driving.
我在开车了。
This is awesome.
太棒了。
Let's turn some music on.
放点音乐吧。
Keep your eyes on the road.
眼睛看着路。
No music.
不许放音乐。
We are coming up to a red light.
前面有红灯。
Step on the brakes.
踩刹车。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I said the brakes.
我说了踩刹车。
Look out for those people.
小心那些人。
Get off the sidewalk.
开下人行道。
Get out of my way.
别挡我的路。
Oh, this is just like playing video games.
哦，这就像玩电子游戏一样。
It's the police.
是警察。
Pull over.
靠边停车。
They'll never take me alive.
他们休想活捉我。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now, why don't we take a look at four key phrases in Fluency Builder.
那么现在，我们来看看“流利度构建”中的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Well, the first phrase is maybe the most important when driving.
嗯，第一个短语可能是开车时最重要的。
It's the first thing you do.
这是你做的第一件事。
You start the car.
你发动车子。
All right, so you don't say you turn on the car, right?
好的，所以你不会说“打开车”，对吧？
No.
不会。
So you put the key in the ignition and you start the car.
所以你把钥匙插进点火开关，然后发动车子。
That means you turn it on.
意思就是把它启动。
What about when you want to turn off the car?
那你想关掉车子时怎么说？
Turn the car off.
关掉车子。
You say stop the engine.
你说“停止引擎”。
Stop the car.
停车。
Stop the engine, right?
停止引擎，对吧？
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
Moving on, our next phrase is a million times.
继续，下一个短语是“一百万次”。
Why is this a phrase, a million times?
为什么“一百万次”是个短语？
It's pretty literal, right?
这很字面，对吧？
We've been through this a million times.
我们已经经历过这个一百万次了。
Well, no, it's not literal.
嗯，不，这不是字面意思。
Otherwise, I think I might kill the person.
否则，我想我可能会杀了那个人。
Because a million times means that we've had this same conversation many, many, many times.
因为“一百万次”意味着我们有过同样的对话很多很多很多次。
But you can't actually have it a million times.
但你不可能真的经历一百万次。
That's way too many.
那太多了。
So it's an exaggeration.
所以这是一种夸张。
Yeah, it's a way to say a lot.
是的，这是一种表示“很多”的方式。
A lot.
很多。
So I've heard him say this a million times.
所以我听他说过这个一百万次了。
I've heard this story a million times.
我听过这个故事一百万次了。
Or I've done this.
或者我做过这个。
I've turned the car on a million times.
我发动过车子一百万次了。
Okay, awesome.
好的，太棒了。
And now, well, they were driving and they heard a police siren and the guy told her to pull over.
现在，嗯，他们正在开车，听到了警笛声，那人让她靠边停车。
Okay, so this is a very common car phrase again, especially when you're dealing with the police.
好的，所以这又是一个非常常见的开车短语，尤其是当你和警察打交道时。
So to pull over means to slow the car down and to stop it on the side of the road.
所以“靠边停车”意思是减速并把车停在路边。
So you could hear a policeman say, pull over.
所以你可能会听到警察说：“靠边停车。”
So pull over your car.
所以把你的车靠边停下。
That means slow down and stop the car on the side.
意思就是减速并把车停在路边。
Because obviously you can't stop in the middle of the road.
因为显然你不能停在路中间。
Right.
对。
And sometimes your mobile phone will ring as well.
有时候你的手机也会响。
And you don't have a hands-free, so you have to pull over to the side so you can pick up the phone.
而且你没有免提设备，所以你必须靠边停车才能接电话。
Usually, right?
通常是这样，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Or you could say, hey, mom, could you pull over?
或者你可以说：“嘿，妈妈，你能靠边停车吗？”
I have to use the restroom.
我得用一下洗手间。
Exactly.
没错。
Awesome.
太棒了。
All right.
好的。
And our last phrase for today is to take me alive, to take someone alive.
我们今天的最后一个短语是“活捉我”，“活捉某人”。
They'll never take me alive.
他们休想活捉我。
That's what the character says.
这就是那个角色说的。
And so this is a phrase that we use when we're talking about people who are running away from the law.
所以这是一个我们在谈论逃避法律追捕的人时使用的短语。
So he says, they'll never capture me.
所以他说：“他们永远抓不到我。”
And if they do, I'll be dead.
“如果他们抓到我，那我也是死的。”
So he's saying either I run free or I die.
所以他是在说：“要么我自由地跑掉，要么我死。”
All right.
好的。
So to take someone alive is basically that.
所以“活捉某人”基本上就是这个意思。
But is it literal?
但这是字面意思吗？
Would you say?
你会这么说吗？
No, this is not literal.
不，这不是字面意思。
He's saying, they'll never catch me.
他是在说：“他们永远抓不到我。”
OK.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the phrases we have for today.
这就是我们今天所有的短语。
Why don't we listen to this dialogue for the last time.
我们最后再听一遍这段对话吧。
And we'll be back.
然后我们就回来。
OK.
好的。
I'm ready for my driving lesson.
我准备好上驾驶课了。
Should I start the car?
我应该发动车子吗？
Hold on there, Fittipaldi.
等等，菲蒂帕尔迪。
First, let's go over things one more time.
首先，我们再过一遍事情。
Now, before you even think of starting the car, make sure your seat is at a comfortable position and you can grip the steering wheel firmly.
现在，在你甚至想发动车子之前，确保你的座位在舒适的位置，并且你能牢牢握住方向盘。
Next, check your rear view mirrors to make sure you can see properly.
接下来，检查你的后视镜，确保你能看清楚。
We've been through this a million times.
我们已经经历过这个一百万次了。
Let's get going already.
我们赶紧出发吧。
I'm ready.
我准备好了。
Fine.
好吧。
Start the car.
发动车子。
OK.
好的。
Now gently step on the clutch and shift to first gear.
现在轻轻踩下离合器，挂到一档。
Good.
不错。
Now accelerate gently and let go of the clutch as you do it.
现在，轻轻加速，同时松开离合器。
There we go.
这就对了。
Good.
不错。
I'm doing it.
我正在做呢。
I'm driving.
我在开车了。
This is awesome.
太棒了。
Let's turn some music on.
放点音乐吧。
Keep your eyes on the road.
眼睛看着路。
No music.
不许放音乐。
We are coming up to a red light.
前面有红灯。
Step on the brakes.
踩刹车。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I said the brakes.
我说踩刹车。
Look out for those people.
小心那些人。
Get off the sidewalk.
离开人行道。
Get out of my way.
别挡我的路。
Oh, this is just like playing video games.
哦，这就像玩电子游戏一样。
It's the police.
是警察。
Pull over.
靠边停车。
They'll never take me alive.
他们休想活捉我。
All right.
好吧。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So this is interesting because as you mentioned, a lot of people in America usually have automatic
这很有趣，因为正如你提到的，很多美国人通常开自动挡
transmissions, whereas in Europe maybe they have manual transmissions.
车，而在欧洲，他们可能开手动挡车。
Exactly.
没错。
Is there a reason for that, do you think?
你觉得这有什么原因吗？
I'm not sure what the reason would be.
我不确定原因是什么。
I think a lot of American car makers manufacture more automatic cars in general.
我认为很多美国汽车制造商总体上生产更多自动挡车。
Some people say that it's because people in America are less concerned with gas, but if
有人说这是因为美国人不太在意油耗，但如果你
you have a manual transmission, you can actually conserve a bit of gas.
开手动挡车，实际上可以节省一些油。
And so because gas prices in Europe are higher generally, more people are interested in having
而且因为欧洲的油价通常更高，所以更多人倾向于开
manual transmissions.
手动挡车。
Also, I remember when I was younger, my dad always bought cars that had a manual transmission
另外，我记得小时候，我爸爸总是买手动挡车，
because he said that if ever they break down, it's much easier and cheaper to fix a car
因为他说如果车坏了，修手动挡车比修自动挡车
that has a manual transmission than it is to fix an automatic one.
更容易也更便宜。
That's right.
没错。
Well, and I personally think that it's better to learn how to drive on a manual transmission
嗯，我个人认为最好先学开手动挡车，
car because you can drive any car afterwards, but if you learn on an automatic, you'll never
因为之后你可以开任何车，但如果先学自动挡，你永远
know how to drive a manual.
不会开手动挡。
There was also a case on television recently about a small child that actually the dialogue
最近电视上也有一个案例，关于一个小孩子，这段对话
is based on it, is he took his dad's car and he was like seven years old and he was driving
就是基于这个案例，他开走了他爸爸的车，他大概七岁，开着车
and was being chased by the police.
被警察追。
No way.
不会吧。
And then he pulled into his house and got out of the car and ran into the house.
然后他把车开进家里，下车跑进了屋子。
So obviously he was an underage driver, but he didn't get into much trouble.
所以显然他是未成年驾驶，但他没惹上什么大麻烦。
But it was interesting because he drove very, very well.
但有趣的是，他开得非常非常好。
That's unbelievable.
真难以置信。
And basically almost learned it by game simulators, by video games on how you drive on a video game.
而且他基本上是通过游戏模拟器、电子游戏学会开车的，就像在游戏里开车一样。
Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
Yeah, so.
是啊，所以。
Well, NASCAR, here he comes.
嗯，纳斯卡赛车，他来了。
Right.
对。
So if you have any questions, any comments or any other suggestions for lessons, please
所以如果你有任何问题、任何评论或其他课程建议，请
come to our website, EnglishPod.com and we'll see you guys there.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里见。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Bye.
再见。